Daniel Duclos-Cavalcanti

Computer Engineer

516-912-7975 | New York, NY | U.S. Citizen | me@duclos.dev | www.duclos.dev | linkedin | github

Summary

Creative thinker and problem-solver with a masters and bachelors in traditional german electrical engineering. Today, I am in New York, collaborating on exciting research with Dr.Sivaraman (NYU) that envisions a financial exchange on the cloud.

Technical Skills

Languages: C, C++, Python, Golang, Rust, Bash, Lua, VHDL, Tcl, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Tools: Terraform, Docker, Packer, AWS, Google Cloud (GCP), Git, Unix Shell, Makefile, CMake, Linux, Jenkins, Vim Technologies: Cloud Computing, Computer Networking, Machine Learning, SoC, FPGA, RTOS, IoT, HPC, TinyML

Frameworks: ZeroMQ, DPDK, Tensorflow, TFLite, Numpy, Pandas, OpenMPI, OpenMP, Xilinx Vivado

Certificates: UCSD: Data Structures Fundamentals, UT Austin: Embedded Systems - uC I/O

Experience

Research Assistant

Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

TU Munich

Munich, Germany • Generated reports to establish a Design-Space Exploration framework to guide ML model deployments.

- Evaluated and compared the performance of various Machine Learning models across GPUs, CPUs and TPUs.
- Analyzed USB traffic through PyShark between the host and externally added TPUs.

Embedded Engineer Intern

Aug 2021 – Jan 2022

Ottobrunn, Germany

- Developed tooling for state simulations of their electric motor via Linux's virtual CAN interface and mock APIs.
- Added unit-tests and code coverage to safety critical features of their motor drive embedded controller.
- Extended an automatic firmware update functionality used by over 20 clients.
- Streamlined build and testing workflows via Jenkins and CMake for a team of over 10 engineers.

Tutor - Embedded Systems Programming Lab

Apr 2021 – Aug 2021

TU Munich

Molabo GmbH

Munich, Germany

• Supervised and aided 20+ students on their final embedded FreeRTOS laboratory projects in C.

Publications

Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud | (Paper)

Jan 24 – Present

- Novel cloud hosted financial exchange achieving low latency multicast service for up to 1000 market participants.
- Achieves better scalability and around 50% lower latency than the multicast service provided by AWS.
- Used kernel-bypass techniques (DPDK) to achieve ultra-low latency at up to 35K multicast packet rate.

Projects

Open-MPI Value Iteration | C++, Multi-Threaded, HPC

Sept 2021 - Feb 2022

Asynchronous value iteration model to distribute workload on an HPC cluster.

Hamming Code Error Detection | C, VHDL, FPGA, SoC

Oct 2022 - March 2023

• Error detection/correction algorithm for packet transmission on Microsemi's SF2 FPGA/SoC.

FreeRTOS-SpaceInvaders | C, RTOS, Multi-Threaded

Aug 2020 – March 2021

• Implemented the famous arcade game as a multi-threaded FreeRTOS application in C.

EDUCATION

New York University: Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences

Sept 2023 – May 2024

Computer Science - Visiting Non-Degree Graduate Student

GPA 4.0

• Co-Authored Publication: Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud • Related Coursework: Operating Systems, Technologies in Finance

Technical University of Munich

Oct 2020 - Sept 2024

M.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering

Expected GPA: 3.2

• M.Sc. Thesis: VM Selection Heuristic for Multicast Overlay Trees in the Cloud

• Related Coursework: Machine Learning Methods and Tools, Embedded Design for Machine Learning, Chips Multicore Processors, Secure SoCs for IoT, High Performance Computing for Machine Intelligence

Technical University of Munich

Oct 2016 - Sept 2020

B.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering